Matmat had a breakdown recalling of his accident at the river.
انهار مطمت وهو يتذكر الحادث الذي تعرض له في النهر.
But why do I feel like it's my fault?
ولكن لماذا أشعر أن هذا خطئي؟
Talk to your siblings. So they can finally come home.
تحدث مع إخوتك، حتى يتمكنوا أخيرًا من العودة إلى المنزل.
Is it true his brother wanted him dead before?
هل صحيح أن أخاه أراد قتله من قبل؟
- Stop gossiping! - Stop it!
- توقف عن الثرثرة! - توقف عن ذلك!
You don't know him!
أنت لا تعرفه!
It seems it was just a simple fight with his brother.
يبدو أنه كان مجرد قتال بسيط مع أخيه.
Don't underestimate a simple misunderstanding.
لا تستهين بسوء الفهم البسيط.
A simple misunderstanding could cost someone their life.
سوء فهم بسيط قد يكلف شخصًا حياته.
Bro, take a look at your palm.
أخي، ألقي نظرة على راحة يدك.
It might just remind you why you shouldn't be with Mia.
ربما يذكرك هذا فقط لماذا لا ينبغي لك أن تكون مع ميا.
I was just a dream. But I'm awake now.
كنتُ مجرد حلم، لكنني استيقظتُ الآن.
I'm back to reality now.
لقد عدت إلى الواقع الآن.
Talk to me.
تحدث معي.
You can't just ignore me.
لا يمكنك تجاهلني.
-
-
Matmat?
جيد؟
Oh, no.
أوه، لا.
I think Matmat is asleep.
أعتقد أن مطماطة نائم.
How will he eat the chicken barbecue I brought?
كيف سيأكل دجاج الشواء الذي أحضرته؟
-
-
What a shame!
يا له من عار!
It smells so good. I cooked it myself at my restaurant.
رائحته طيبة جدًا. طبخته بنفسي في مطعمي.
I even brought hot soup that Mama Li cooked.
حتى أنني أحضرت حساءً ساخنًا طهته ماما لي.
Oh, wow!
أوه، واو!
Well, I guess I should just go.
حسنًا، أعتقد أنه يجب علي أن أذهب.
I need to go back to my restaurant.
أحتاج إلى العودة إلى مطعمي.
What shall I do with these? Who will eat the barbecue and
ماذا أفعل بهذه؟ من سيأكل الشواء؟
Mama Li's hot soup?
حساء ماما لي الساخن؟
What do I do? Hmm…
ماذا أفعل؟ هممم...
What do I do?
ماذا أفعل؟
I'll just leave it here on the brown table.
سأتركه هنا على الطاولة البنية.
Right next to Matmat.
بجوار مطماطة مباشرة.
Alright.
على ما يرام.
I'll be off now.
سأذهب الآن.
Thank you, Mama Li and Jason.
شكرا لك ماما لي وجيسون.
Hmm?
همم؟
Jason?
جيسون؟
Jason's not here?
جيسون ليس هنا؟
"KILLING THE ENCHANTED WITCH"
"قتل الساحرة المسحورة"
"The little brother
"الأخ الصغير
killed his big brother."
"قتل أخاه الأكبر."
Patrick?
باتريك؟
How were you able to change clothes without coming home?
كيف تمكنت من تغيير ملابسك دون العودة إلى المنزل؟
What about your undergarments?
ماذا عن ملابسك الداخلية؟
Here.
هنا.
I bought it for you.
لقد اشتريته لك.
It's your size.
إنه حجمك.
I checked your things at home to be sure.
لقد قمت بفحص أغراضك في المنزل للتأكد.
It's big…
إنه كبير…
Mia!
لي!
The closet's big.
الخزانة كبيرة.
Can we talk now?
هل يمكننا التحدث الآن؟
I'm still working.
لا أزال أعمل.
I didn't call you yesterday because you said you were taking care of Matmat.
لم أتصل بك بالأمس لأنك قلت أنك تعتني بمتمات.
Now that you're not busy with him, can we talk?
الآن بعد أن لم تعد مشغولاً به، هل يمكننا التحدث؟
Fine. Let's talk.
حسناً، دعنا نتحدث.
- Here, hold this. - Okay.
- هنا، امسك هذا. - حسنًا.
That's Patrick's.
هذا باتريك.
Don't touch it.
لا تلمسه.
Okay.
تمام.
Hey! Didn't she just say not to touch it?
مهلا! ألم تقل لي للتو ألا تلمسه؟
She knows Patrick's size?
هل تعرف حجم باتريك؟
That's how close they are?
هل هذا هو مدى قربهم؟
I told you.
أخبرتك.
I told you they're together.
لقد قلت لك أنهم معًا.
Tsk! Give me that!
تسك! أعطني هذا!
Patrick.
باتريك.
Are you mad at me,
هل أنت غاضب مني،
because you didn't tell Matmat the truth about of our trip?
لأنك لم تخبر مطماطة الحقيقة بشأن رحلتنا؟
I'm not mad.
أنا لست مجنونة.
Then why aren't you talking to me?
إذن لماذا لا تتحدث معي؟
Matmat is all I have time to worry about right now.
ماتمات هو كل ما لدي من وقت للقلق بشأنه الآن.
About your past?
عن ماضيك؟
Because he recalled how you wanted him dead?
لأنه تذكر كيف كنت تريد قتله؟
That's not your fault.
هذا ليس خطأك.
- You're only saying that because-- - No.
- أنت تقول ذلك فقط لأن-- - لا.
I know it's not your fault.
أعرف أن هذا ليس خطؤك.
Because I saw everything.
لأني رأيت كل شيء.
I was there.
كنت هناك.
You didn't push him.
لم تضغط عليه.
It was an accident, him falling into the river
لقد كان حادثًا، سقوطه في النهر
I even wished you'd let him drown.
حتى أنني تمنيت أن تتركه يغرق.
But you were a poor little boy,
ولكنك كنت طفلا فقيرا،
who loved his brother.
الذي أحب أخاه.
You saved him.
لقد انقذته.
I know that.
وأنا أعلم ذلك.
But it doesn't mean my conscience is clear
ولكن هذا لا يعني أن ضميري مرتاح
about what happened.
حول ما حدث.
There you go again.
ها أنت ذا مرة أخرى.
Stop playing hostage and victim to your family.
توقف عن لعب دور الرهينة والضحية لعائلتك.
You didn't commit a murder.
لم ترتكب جريمة قتل.
It's not your fault your brother fell into the river.
ليس خطأك أن أخاك سقط في النهر.
See?
يرى؟
I can be the key to break all of your chains.
أستطيع أن أكون المفتاح لكسر جميع سلاسلك.
Come with me.
تعال معي.
Live with me.
عيش معي.
I can't, Mia.
لا أستطيع، ميا.
Come on, Patrick.
تعال يا باتريك.
Even after Matmat admitted he's been holding a grudge against you,
حتى بعد أن اعترف مطماطة بأنه كان يحمل ضغينة ضدك،
do you think he still want to be with you?
هل تعتقد أنه لا زال يريد أن يكون معك؟
I can't go with you, Mia.
لا أستطيع الذهاب معك، ميا.
I don't believe you.
أنا لا أصدقك.
What you say is different from what I see.
ما تقوله يختلف عما أراه.
Mia, don't twist my words!
ميا، لا تحرفي كلامي!
I'm only saying what I see!
أنا فقط أقول ما أرى!
That was just a dream, okay?
لقد كان مجرد حلم، أليس كذلك؟
Us swimming in the sea, that night we spent together,
نحن نسبح في البحر، تلك الليلة التي قضيناها معًا،
everything we shared that morning, all of that was just a dream!
كل ما شاركناه في ذلك الصباح، كان مجرد حلم!
Are you hallucinating?
هل أنت تعاني من الهلوسة؟
We were really together in Montanesa!
لقد كنا حقا معا في مونتانيسا!
Yes.
نعم.
And now it's just a memory.
والآن أصبح مجرد ذكرى.
That's all it'll ever be.
هذا كل ما سيكون عليه الأمر.
Are you cutting me out of your life
هل تقطعني من حياتك؟
just to try to make up for your past with your brother?!
فقط لمحاولة التعويض عن ماضيك مع أخيك؟!
Mia, we were kids when he almost drowned.
ميا، كنا أطفالاً عندما كاد أن يغرق.
I didn't know better then.
لم أكن أعرف أفضل حينها.
I didn't realize I was hurting Matmat.
لم أكن أدرك أنني كنت أؤذي ماتمات.
Now it's my fault…
الآن أصبح خطئي...
because when I'm with you, it's like he doesn't exist.
لأنه عندما أكون معك، يبدو الأمر وكأنه غير موجود.
It's wrong that I keep forgetting Matmat.
من الخطأ أن أنسى مطمت باستمرار.
It was a mistake that I ever entertained having you in my life when we met again.
لقد كان من الخطأ أن أستمتع بوجودك في حياتي عندما التقينا مرة أخرى.
What about when you said you were free because of me?
ماذا عن عندما قلت أنك حر بفضلي؟
Was that also a mistake?
هل كان هذا خطأ أيضا؟
My reality is clearer to me now.
حقيقتي أصبحت أوضح بالنسبة لي الآن.
Stop lying.
توقف عن الكذب
That's why Matmat calls you a liar.
لهذا السبب ماتمات يدعوك كاذبًا.
That's the truth.
هذه هي الحقيقة.
Enough.
كافٍ.
Patrick, please.
باتريك، من فضلك.
Mia, let's end this.
ميا، دعونا ننهي هذا.
Stop holding on to what we had.
توقف عن التمسك بما كان لدينا.
This is where it ends for us.
وهنا ينتهي الأمر بالنسبة لنا.
Patrick!
باتريك!
Patrick, come back!
باتريك، عد إلى هنا!
That was just a dream, okay?
لقد كان مجرد حلم، أليس كذلك؟
Us swimming in the sea, that night we spent together,
نحن نسبح في البحر، تلك الليلة التي قضيناها معًا،
everything we shared that morning, all of it was just a dream.
كل ما شاركناه في ذلك الصباح، كان مجرد حلم.
We were really together in Montanesa!
لقد كنا حقا معا في مونتانيسا!
Yes.
نعم.
And now it's just a memory.
والآن أصبح مجرد ذكرى.
That's all it'll ever be.
هذا كل ما سيكون عليه الأمر.
Are you cutting me out of your life
هل تقطعني من حياتك؟
just to make up for your past with your brother?!
فقط لتعويض ماضيك مع أخيك؟!
Mia, we were kids when he almost drowned.
ميا، كنا أطفالاً عندما كاد أن يغرق.
I didn't know better then.
لم أكن أعرف أفضل حينها.
I didn't realize I was hurting Matmat.
لم أكن أدرك أنني كنت أؤذي ماتمات.
Now it's my fault…
الآن أصبح خطئي...
because when I'm with you, it's like he doesn't exist.
لأنه عندما أكون معك، يبدو الأمر وكأنه غير موجود.
It's wrong that I keep forgetting Matmat.
من الخطأ أن أنسى مطمت باستمرار.
Even after Matmat has admitted
حتى بعد أن اعترف مطمت
he's been holding a grudge against you,
لقد كان يحمل ضغينة ضدك،
do you think he still wants to be with you?
هل تعتقد أنه لا زال يريد أن يكون معك؟
Luis.
لويس.
I'm so tired.
أنا متعب جدا.
Why did you have to go?
لماذا كان عليك أن تذهب؟
Why did you leave us so early?
لماذا تركتنا مبكرا؟
Luis, your sons need you.
لويس، أبناؤك بحاجة إليك.
They really do.
إنهم يفعلون ذلك حقا.
They're so naughty.
إنهم شقيون للغاية.
Ma?
و؟
Patrick.
باتريك.
Patrick, my son, come here.
باتريك، ابني، تعال هنا.
Come here.
تعال الى هنا.
Aw, Patrick.
أوه، باتريك.
My sweet son.
ابني الحبيب.
Don't leave your brother alone, okay?
لا تترك أخاك وحده، حسنًا؟
Always take care of him.
اعتني به دائما.
Always stand up for him, okay?
قف بجانبه دائمًا، حسنًا؟
Take care of him for life.
اعتني به مدى الحياة.
Ow!
أوه!
Ow! It hurts!
آه! إنه يؤلمني!
Patpat! It hurts, Patpat!
عصا! إنه يؤلمني، عصا!
Patpat, it hurts!
العصا، انها تؤلم!
Look at you. You got hurt.
انظر إليك، لقد أُصبت.
Yes, Patpat.
نعم ، عصا.
Patpat, you forgot your boxing gloves.
باتبات، لقد نسيت قفازات الملاكمة الخاصة بك.
These are for Patpat.
هذه لباتبات.
This is for Matmat.
هذا لماتمات.
Dino Boy!
دينو بوي!
This is mine, and those are yours, right?
هذه لي، وهذه لك، أليس كذلك؟
M-Miss Mia or Matmat?
آنسة ميا أم مطمات؟
Of course, it's you, Matmat.
بالطبع، أنت، ماتمات.
Liar!
كذاب!
You're a liar!
أنت كاذب!
You told Mama you wanted me gone!
لقد قلت لأمي أنك تريد رحيلي!
"I hope Matmat just dies!"
"أتمنى أن يموت ماتمات!"
You told Mama you wanted me dead!
لقد قلت لأمي أنك تريدني ميتًا!
You want me dead!
تريدني ميتا!
I hope he just dies!
أتمنى أن يموت فقط!
I hope Matmat dies!
أتمنى أن يموت مطمت!
P-Patpat!
عصا P!
Patpat!
يلزق!
Pat--
بات--
Patpat--
يلزق--
Matmat!
شكرًا لك!
- Matmat. - Patpat.
- عصا.
Mama is still alive.
ماما لا تزال على قيد الحياة.
Mama is in heaven now.
ماما في الجنة الآن.
We can't be with Mama anymore.
لم نعد قادرين على البقاء مع أمي بعد الآن.
Just like Trexy…
تمامًا مثل تريكسي…
Trexy's mother left him.
تركت والدة تريكسي ابنها.
- But-- - Mama left Matmat.
- لكن --- تركت أمي مطماطة.
- I'm still here, Matmat. - Mama left him.
- أنا لا أزال هنا، ماتمات. - تركته ماما.
I'm still here for you.
أنا لا أزال هنا من أجلك.
I'm not leaving you.
انا لا أتركك.
I'll be with you everywhere you go.
سأكون معك في كل مكان تذهب إليه.
You and me, Patpat?
أنت وأنا، باتبات؟
Yes, Matmat.
نعم، مطمت.
Matmat and Patpat, right?
ماتمات وباتبات، أليس كذلك؟
Only Matmat and Patpat?
فقط ماتمات وباتبات؟
Yes.
نعم.
Only Matmat and Patpat.
فقط مطمت وباتبات.
Don't leave your brother alone, okay?
لا تترك أخاك وحده، حسنًا؟
Always take care of him.
اعتني به دائما.
Always stand up for him, okay?
قف بجانبه دائمًا، حسنًا؟
- Take care of him for life.
- اعتني به مدى الحياة.
Happy day.
يوم سعيد.
You can't resist me.
لا يمكنك مقاومتي.
We have to end up together.
علينا أن ننتهي معًا.
Mama Dinosaur is so kind.
ماما الديناصور لطيفة جدًا.
But Bunso is not.
ولكن بونسو ليس كذلك.
Whatever you two went through
مهما مررتم به
is just part of who you are today.
هو مجرد جزء من شخصيتك اليوم.
Think about your own happiness too.
فكر في سعادتك أيضًا.
That's not being selfish.
هذا ليس أنانية.
- Where's Mia? - She's at her house.
- أين ميا؟ - إنها في منزلها.